Marguerite(YuChen) Mei

(647) 997-5519 | mgrtmei@gmail.com | Toronto, ON

Core Competency

Master of Management, Accounting & Finance, 4 years' analytical experience in Financial Analysis, Corp Accounting, CRM and Marketing. Strong technical thinking, hands on implementation in various data reconciliation, transformation and data visualization projects. A true problem solver and team player!

Qualification

✓ Financial Analyses

Finance & Accounting, Reconciliation & Auditing, Budget & Forecasting, SAP Order-to-Cash Cycle;

✓ CRM & Marketing

Banking Customer Migration & Segmentation; Market Share; Campaign Analysis; LVMH

✓ Data Analyses

Data Integration, Data Quality & Cleansing; Data Gap Analysis; DB queries & Semantic layer

✓ Data Visualization

Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics, KPI design, Report Automation, Business Requirement Collection

Tech Skills

- Data: Advanced SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Google Analytics, MS Access, Enterprise Excel, VBA, Python
- Application & Tools: SAP Sales & Distribution, SPSS, draw.io, Jira, Confluence, ServiceNow, Windows Task Scheduler
- Platform: SQL Server, Snowflake, Azure Cloud, Databricks, Data warehouse

Education

Master of Management, Accounting and Finance	University of Windsor	Sep 2020 - Jun 2022
Bachelor of Commerce with Honors	York University, ON	Sep 2014 - Oct 2019
Diploma certificate, Professional Accounting	Seneca College, ON	Sep 2019 - Aug 2020
Certificate: Google Analytics Basic & Advanced, Digital Campaign	Google	Aug 2022

Work Experience

Data Analyst EDPYPF Services Inc.

Jun 2022 - Current

- Banking transaction analysis via RFM model on customer migration and segmentation for launching new credit card
- Designed Power BI dashboard on expense control with YoY and actual vs. budget analysis
- Collected business requirement through business meeting, data investigation to identify business logic & KPI formula etc
- Monthly Income Statement Reporting Automation using VBA in Access and Excel, which saved 80% time on repeated work
- Answered various ad hoc business questions and analyzed industry trends in Customer Sales database and action on closing gaps with resolving data duplicate and data integrity issues

Financial Analyst

Ginis Electronics Technology LLC

May 2021 - Aug 2021

- Worked with bank, internal / external stakeholders on accounting related, like financing, insurance, securities, credit cards, finance income statement and balance sheet.
- Accounts bookkeeping maintenance and data reconciliation for GL, AP, AR in SQL Server 2014
- Worked with 3rd party company on monthly, quarterly and yearly adjustment, posting, auditing and financial reporting
- Automated invoicing process through Excel Marco, VBA to upload invoice data to accounting table in database.
- Managed 10+ marketing channels across multiple industries seeking for business opportunities in short turnover periods; Arranged project set-up and execution liaising with certain regional demand analyses
- Analyzed and grasped client core demands quickly; Well-prepared with explicit business workflow, objectives, and deliveries

Business Analyst

Axis Communications Inc.

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Collaborated with stakeholders from sales and service teams to collect business requirements and lead initiative solutions in data manipulation process; Prepared SQL queries for routine and ad hoc analysis
- Planned event for distributors training campaign, creating contents, tracking, analyzing subscribers
- Developed potential customer through questionnaire and interviews & identified core group through scoring based selection
- Made strategy presentation; praised by C-level clients for research-based insights, establishing new business opportunities

Projects Experience

•	Bell strategies to accelerate prepaid gross subscriber additions	University of Windsor	May 2022
•	Customer based Brand Equity Management Project	University of Windsor	Dec 2021
•	Marty's Department Store – Customer Grouping & Campaign Analyses	York University	Sep 2020